<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Event Id="984597" lastUpdate="Saturday, January 22, 2005 at 12:22:37am GMT" eventTypeId="1" eventTypeName="Earning Conference Call/Presentation">
  <EventStory Id="984597.F" expirationDate="Friday, January 21, 2005 at 4:30:00pm GMT" action="publish" storyType="transcript" version="Final">
    <Headline><![CDATA[Edited Transcript of UB.N^K08 earnings conference call or presentation 21-Jan-05 4:30pm GMT]]></Headline>
    <Body><![CDATA[Q4 2004 UnionBanCal Earnings Conference Call

SAN FRANCISCO Jan 22, 2005 (Thomson StreetEvents) -- Edited Transcript of MUFG Americas Holdings Corp earnings conference call or presentation Friday, January 21, 2005 at 4:30:00pm GMT

TEXT version of Transcript

================================================================================
Corporate Participants
================================================================================
   *  Jack Rice
      Union Bank of California - VP, IR
   *  David Matson
      Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO
   *  Phil Flynn
      Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman
   *  Rick Hartnack
      Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman

================================================================================
Conference Call Participants
================================================================================
   *  Heather Wolf
      Merrill Lynch - Analyst
   *  Brian Harvey
      Fox-Pitt Kelton - Analyst
   *  Manuel Ramirez
      Keefe Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst
   *  Andrea Jao
      Lehman Brothers - Analyst
   *  Jed Gore
      Sanova Capital - Analyst
   *  Gary Townsend
      Friedman Billings Ramsey - Analyst
   *  Campbell Chaney
      Sanders Morris - Analyst
   *  Brian Kahn
      Sandler O'Neill - Analyst
   *  Chris Chouinard
      Morgan Stanley - Analyst
   *  Joe Morford
      RBC Capital Markets - Analyst
   *  Kathy Steinbrecher
      Piper Jaffray - Analyst
   *  Lana Chan
      Advest - Analyst

================================================================================
Presentation
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to the Union Bank of California fourth quarter 2004 earnings conference call. (OPERATOR INSTRUCTIONS). At this time, it is my pleasure to turn our conference over to the manager of Investor Relations, Mr. Jack Rice. Please go ahead, sir.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Rice,  Union Bank of California - VP, IR   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. This is Jack Rice, and on the call this morning are Phil Flynn, Vice Chairman of the Company, Rick Hartnack, Vice Chairman of the Company, and David Matson, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer. David Anderson, Senior Vice President and Controller is here as well. Mr. Matson will first review fourth quarter's financial performance, including remarks about credit quality. Then Mr. Flynn will review highlights and commercial financial services quarterly and full-year performance and provide some details on our balance sheet changes and net interest margin dynamics. Then Mr. Hartnack will discuss community banking and investment services performance and outlook as well as details regarding the operating environment and economic outlook in California. We will then open the call for questions and answers. We ask that each of you limit your questions to one lead and a maximum of one follow-up question so that we may accommodate all questioners.
 Before we begin, this conference call includes forward-looking statements that involve risks and uncertainties. Forward-looking statements can be identified by looking at the fact that they do not relate strictly to historical or current facts. Often they include the words believe, expect, anticipate, intend, plan, estimate, project, or words of similar meaning or future or conditional verbs such as will, would, should, could or may.
 A number of important factors could cause actual results to differ materially from those in the forward-looking statements. Those factors include fluctuations in interest rates, government policies and regulations and their enforcement including monetary and fiscal policies and bank secrecy act related matters, legislation, economic conditions, credit quality of borrowers, operational factors, and competition in the geographic and business areas in which the Company conducts its operations, global, political, and general economic conditions.
 A complete description of the Company including related risk factors is discussed in the Company's public filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. All forward-looking statements included in this conference call are based on information available at the time of the call and the Company assumes no obligation to update any forward-looking statements. Thank you and now Mr. Matson with the quarter's financial review.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you for joining us this morning. Operating earnings for the fourth quarter 2004 were $1.19 per share, 13 percent higher than last year. This increase was driven by strong deposit and loan growth, higher non-interest income, improved asset quality. Fourth quarter net interest income was 11 percent higher than last year. This growth was driven by a 14 percent increase in earning assets which was funded by continued growth in core deposits. Notably our demand deposits grew 17 percent over last year. The strong growth in earning assets and deposits were partially offset by the effects of a flatter yield curve, and planned runoff in hedge income which contributed $23 million less in income than in the prior year.
 Growth in earning assets was primarily driven by strong growth in our commercial and mortgage lending activities. On the liability side, we continued to benefit from core deposit-gathering capabilities and expanded the non-interest-bearing portion of our deposit base to 48 percent of total deposits in the fourth quarter, while also increasing total deposits 13 percent over fourth quarter of 2003.
 Non-interest income was up 13 percent, primarily due to increases and service charges on deposit accounts, trust and investment management fees, and insurance commissions. A $19 million increase in private equity gains was largely offset by a $16 million increase in losses on the sale of securities. Fourth quarter non-interest expense was up 12 percent year-over-year; approximately 5 percentage points of this increase was attributable to our acquisition and de novo expansion activity. Of the remaining 7 percentage points of increase almost half of it was attributable to higher pension and other post-retirement expenses, higher professional fees, and higher vendor bill associated with our title in escrow activities, along with an annual merit increase account for the remainder. The fourth quarter provision for credit losses was -10 million, reflecting continued improvement in overall asset quality, and net recoveries of $4 million for the quarter. Nonperforming assets declined 14 percent during the quarter.
 Full-year results were also strong. Operating earnings per share was up 16 percent over 2003, driven by strong demand deposit growth. A 13 percent increase in non-interest income, and a big reduction in provision expense. For the full year, net charge-offs were only $27 million or 10 basis points of the average total loans, compared with $162 million in 2003. Nonperforming assets were reduced $125 million or 43 percent during 2004.
 Return on equity on an operating basis was 16.7 percent in 2004, an improvement of 144 basis points over 2003. Our strong capital generation supported a 16 percent increase in the dividend in April, as well as the repurchase of 3.6 million shares in 2004. Our tangible common equity ratio was 7.89 percent at year-end 2004, within our strategic target range of 7 to 8 percent.
 Finally, let's discuss our earnings outlook for 2005. We currently expect full-year 2005 earnings per share to be in the range of $4.57 to $4.77 per share. This guidance is based on the following expectations. Double-digit growth in average loans compared to 2004. This includes the full-year impact of the Jackson Federal acquisition, which will increase average loans of approximately $1 billion year-over-year. And a mid single digit decline in our average securities. And in total, this will give us our total earning assets -- averaged earnings asset growth of approximately 10 percent.
 We expect non-interest-bearing deposit growth between 7 to 8 percent; we forecast net interest income growth of 6 to 8 percent, compared to the prior year. We expect dollar net interest income to grow, however, we expect to see continued net interest margin compression until the Fed funds target rate rises above 3 percent. Non-interest income should grow in the low single digits compared to 2004. Non-interest expense should increase in the mid single digit range. The provision for credit loss is expected to be in the range of zero to $20 million per year. The full-year 2000 effective tax rate is expected to be approximately 35 percent. Average shares outstanding for the full year are expected to decline by roughly 2 percent.
 Now some additional commentary regarding our expectations for net interest income for 2005. As you know, the yield curve has flattened since our last earnings conference call. We expect some additional flattening over the course of 2005. Our forecast assumes that short (ph) rates will increase an additional 125 basis points and that long rates will rise only 75 to 100 basis points during 2005.
 During 2004, we achieved stable net interest income without sacrificing our ability to benefit from right (ph) raising rates in 2005 and beyond. At the same time, changes over the past few years in the composition of our balance sheet, particularly changes in our loan mix, have resulted in a less asset-sensitive profile than in the past. As such, while we expect growing net interest income, we expect a modest decline in the net interest margin during the first half of 2005 before we begin to see gradual improvement.
 Now let us discuss our asset liability position. Like last quarter, we are using a projected balance sheet as the basis for this outlook discussion. We continue to maintain a relatively neutral risk profile as the parallel shifts in interest rates over the near-term. In anticipation of rising rates we continue to maintain a relatively short duration investment portfolio, with the effective duration of 2.3 at year-end 2004.
 Now I will provide our outlook for the first quarter. Our current expectations for the first quarter earnings is $1.07 to $1.12 per share. Compared to fourth quarter we expect flat net interest income in the first quarter. We anticipate 25 basis points of Fed action in the first quarter. And we generally expect a parallel shift from short- and long-term rates from current levels. Our net interest income forecast also incorporates a reduction in hedge income of approximately $1 million, and the affect of 2 less days in the quarter.
 We expect average non-interest-bearing deposits to be flat on a sequential quarter basis. Average loans should reflect a healthy increase over prior quarter, partially due to a full-year or quarter effect of the Jackson Federal acquisition. We expect a modest decrease in non-interest income. Almost half of this decrease is due to the absence of the unusual items that impacted fourth quarter non-interest income. We anticipate a modest increase in non-interest expense versus the fourth quarter. Substantially all of this expected increase is attributable to customary seasonal increases in staff-related expenses, specifically payroll taxes.
 We expect a provision for credit losses of approximately -$10 million dollars for the first quarter. We estimate an effective tax rate of approximately 35 percent for the quarter. Average shares outstanding are expected to be slightly lower than the fourth quarter. Guidance for both the quarter and the year end excludes the effect of stock options expensing. We expect to begin expensing stock options in the third quarter '05.
 And now onto Phil Flynn, Vice Chairman of our Commercial Financial Services group.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you David. As you have heard, the bank had a very strong fourth quarter and full-year performance. I would like to give you some more detail regarding the Commercial Financial Services group's quarterly and full-year results and discuss our outlook for the coming year. I will also provide some additional high-level commentary on the bank's balance sheet from an ALM perspective.
 During the fourth quarter average CFSG loans were up 11 percent or 1.4 billion to 13.8 billion. Within this total average commercial loans were up approximately 500 million or 7 percent to 7.7 billion. Average real estate loans were up approximately 900 million, or 19 percent to 5.5 billion. The Jackson Federal portfolio accounts for 750 million of this increase. During the year, measuring average fourth quarter 2003 against average fourth quarter 2004, we had point to point commercial loan growth of 1.1 billion, or 16 percent, and average real estate loan growth of 900 million or 20 percent.
 For 2005, we are forecasting continued strong commercial loan growth. Commercial loans should grow approximately 20 to 25 percent over 2004 averages or about 1.5 to 1.8 billion. Some of this strong growth will be related to an approximate $600 million increase in title industry loans, which are a function of rising interest rates.
 Real estate loans should grow at a more modest billion 1 to a billion 4 since the full-year effect of the Jackson portfolio accounts for approximately $900 million. On the deposit side, during the fourth quarter, CSFG's average deposits were up approximately 5 percent or 800 million to 15.1 billion.
 Of this business DDA was up 6 percent or approximately 400 million to 6.6 billion. Title and escrow DDA were up 2 percent or less than 100 million to 3.1 billion. Money market accounts accounted for the rest of the increase, growing approximately 300 million or 10 percent to 3.4 billion. During the year, again measuring average fourth quarter '03 against average fourth quarter '04, we had point to point deposit growth of 1.6 billion or 12 percent. Business DDA grew a very strong 22 percent or 1.2 billion, and title escrow deposits grew 12 percent or 300 million.
 During 2005, we are forecasting more modest deposit growth in CSFG due to our assumption of rising interest rates. We are projecting that total average deposits will grow by about 5 percent of 2004's average. Within the total business DDA should grow by approximately 9 percent while we forecast the title and escrow deposits will decrease by about 6 percent. Non-interest income was up $19 million in the fourth quarter, 35 percent higher than the third quarter due mostly to the private equity gains David referred to.
 For the year non-interest income was up 50 million or 27 percent over 2003 led by strong syndication fees of 17.3 million, 6.7 million higher than '03, and private equity gains of 27.5 million, 26.6 million more than '03. Deposit fees were up a modest 4 million over 2003 as customers began to benefit from rising interest rates in the latter half of the year that drove higher earnings credits with which to pay for banking services.
 In 2005, we expect that deposit fees will decrease modestly from '04 as rates continue to rise. Syndication fees should remain strong and although we anticipate continued private equity gains, they will not likely equal the past year's.
 Non-interest expenses grew 4 million or 8 percent in the fourth quarter primarily due to customer vendor bills paid by the bank and the addition of the Jackson Federal real estate lending business. Going forward the full-year impact of this acquisition will add about 8 million to CSFG's operating expenses. Absent that increase, expenses will grow about 6 percent in '05.
 As mentioned we want to provide some additional perspective on our balance sheet from both a historical and perspective view. In the past, prior to 2000, we had a very asset-sensitive balance sheet, due to our heavy concentration and LIBOR-based floating-rate commercial loans. Over the past four years, we have reduced our concentration of commercial loans and added a significant amount of hybrid ARMs and fixed-rate securities. We did this for several reasons. Most importantly, we decided from our risk management point of view to create a less volatile and more granular balance sheet, which we chose to build with high-quality, low-risk residential mortgages.
 In addition, we have experienced a period of very high growth in our core deposits, coupled with shrinking commercial loans, caused by low demand and the exit of several business lines. Our resultant increase in liquidity caused us to build a sizable securities portfolio. As you know, it has been our long-standing policy to not make aggressive bets on interest rates. Thus, for the past several years as the securities and mortgage portfolios have grown, we have purposely kept their average lives relatively short.
 Throughout 2004, we maintained a very respectable net interest margin of approximately 400 basis points. We have achieved this thanks to our success in attracting core demand deposits that gave us a very low cost of funds and our decision to grow our fixed-rate portfolios and maintain a neutral overall risk profile. During this period of low interest rates, our floating-rate commercial loans have actually detracted from our net interest margin, which has been supported by the incremental spread on our hybrid ARM loans which have been and still are on a fixed-rate phase, the benefit of floating-rate hedges established earlier and the securities portfolio.
 In the latter half of 2004 and going forward into 2005, we have entered a period of rising short-term interest rates. Some analysts have expected that our earnings would immediately reflect the benefits of our perceived asset sensitivity. As explained, our balance sheet is very different than it used to be; approximately 55 percent is in fixed-rate assets. Our cost of funds although among the lowest in the industry is, nonetheless, increasing with rising rates. While we are rapidly expanding our floating-rate commercial loans, due to robust demand, until LIBOR rates increase another 75 to 125 basis points, this portion of our balance sheet will still not add to our expected net interest margin.
 Meanwhile the spread between our cost of funds and the yield on our hybrid ARMs and securities is being compressed. Thus, it will take some time -- probably the balance of '05 -- until rising rates enable floating-rate commercial loans to add to the expected net interest margin and overcome the narrowing spreads on our fixed-rate assets. Nonetheless, we do expect that asset sensitivity will reassert itself as we move through '05 and into '06.
 In summary, we believe that we have prudently managed through a period of historic low rates while maintaining a healthy net interest margin without betting our future by creating a long duration securities portfolio. We have also managed to build a much less volatile loan portfolio that should serve us in the future with lower credit provisions.
 That concludes my remarks and I will turn the call over to Rick who will update on the community bank and investment services group and discuss California's economic climate.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rick Hartnack,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning everyone. Thank you for your interest in Union Bank again. Today I would like to share with you highlights of the fourth quarter and my portion of the bank and the full-year performance results as well. And give an update on our acquisition integration activities and then I will close with a few comments on California's economy.
 The consumer small-business deposit story continues to be a very strong one of growth in sales success. Retail core deposits were up 4.4 billion or 14.8 percent in 2004. Within this core deposits growth, non-interest-bearing deposits were up 17 percent in the fourth quarter over the same period the prior year and 4 percent over the third quarter.
 We generated record deposit fees with deposit fee income growth for the year at 10 percent, and at the bank level, ended 2004 with one of the lowest cost of funds in the industry, 60 basis points. You will continue to note that DDA makes up approximately 48 percent of our deposit funding at the bank level. The small-business credit score portfolio increased 12.7 percent in 2004 reflecting an increased demand in sales success, with the rest of the small-business portfolio finally showing modest increase in the last quarter of the year where previously it had been running flat.
 We have enhanced our capabilities in serving the needs of our clients in the owner occupied real estate market and expect to see good growth over time. Growth and residential real estate originations resulted in portfolio outstandings up 2 billion for the year. Despite continued shrinkage of our discontinued business lines, auto dealer and auto lease, other consumer loans overall increased 7.4 percent.
 Overall, we are confident that we can keep growing our retail franchise by increasing sales in our existing stores and to our existing customers.
 Let me turn now to our trust and investment business. As you know, we have committed to make growth in this business segment a priority and strategic focus. We completed two acquisitions near year end of 2004. Our acquisition of CNA Trust has been going well, our systems integration has been successfully completed, the addition of the CNA revenue to our existing business has created a nearly $60 million revenue business, and we believe positions us as the fifth-largest bank-owned 401(k) recordkeeper in the U.S.
 In December, we completed the transfer of Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi trust U.S.-based trust business to our corporate trust department. This provided us approximately a 40 percent growth in revenues in that business and we believe that this will position us in the top 10 corporate trust providers in the U.S. and our systems integration was completed, simultaneous with the transfer of that business.
 Our strategy to build scale in Union Bank investment services, our wholly-owned brokerage subsidiary, is showing early and encouraging signs. We saw a 27 percent growth in dedicated broker sales during the fourth quarter over the same period prior year, and full-year noninterest income growth of 8 percent. We are elevating the prominence of investments in the bank's line units by increasing the number of financial advisors, while also increasing the population of licensed bankers referring business to our financial advisors.
 All in all, we expect to see healthy growth from our brokerage company in 2005 and forward. As you know, over the last couple of years, we have been refocusing our approach to wealth management; and this year's performance is reflective of the investment we have made in that business. Total wealth management revenue was up 16 percent year-over-year and (technical difficulty) percent over the same quarter last year.
 On the insurance front while agency revenues were up 25 percent year-over-year, we expect that the softening of the market will somewhat dampen (ph) revenue growth in the near-term. In the long term, this will be counteracted by the efficiencies we will gain as we migrate the agencies to a common operating platform. The first location will be converted at the end of this month and we hope to have all the other locations converted by the end of 2005.
 While we had a terrific year in 2004, I'm reminded of that we -- like the rest of the industry -- will have to keep a sharp eye on cost management in 2005. The initiatives to assure that we deliver on the promise are underway now. We also intend to continue to focus our attention on effective and efficient capital management throughout the year as we have for the last several years.
 I would now like to talk a little bit about the California economy and the outlook in our markets. With many of you looking at a large snowstorm bearing down on you, probably the first thing I would say about our economy is 75 degrees and sunny, which is what we are enjoying right now. The California economy is now solidly in the path of sustained growth. The economic recovery now encompasses the regions and industries that have suffered the most from the latest recession.
 The unemployment rate of the San Francisco Bay Area, perhaps the area most seriously affected by the slowdown, has declined significantly from its peak in 2003 and is now below both the national and statewide averages. Payroll employment and growth remains weaker in the San Francisco area than in the Southern and central regions but the area offers much upside potential in coming months because the job recovery is still fairly new here. After shedding more than 350,000 jobs since 2000, the state's manufacturing sector has finally stabilized, poised for renewed growth in 2005.
 On the other hand, service sector employment has been growing strongly, while business and professional services gained in the highest number of jobs over the past year in that sector. Leisure and hospitality in educational and health services categories also gained. The housing boom in California has produced many new jobs in construction financial industries. At the same time the ongoing state fiscal difficulties have resulted in significantly fewer positions in the public sector.
 Overall the pace of job growth increased in 2004 and is expected to accelerate even more in 2005. The California housing market continues to maintain pretty good momentum. In November, the medium price for existing homes increased 23 percent over the same period a year ago. While there are few signs that the market is slowing, such as larger inventories of unsold homes and a longer period required to sell homes, consumer demand seems to be holding up well because of relatively low mortgage rates and positive employment trends. The port of Los Angeles -- Long Beach -- continues to be the country's most important gateway portrayed from China and the Far East. Port traffic's up 44 percent since 1999 and with better coordination of labor and land transportation, we expect solid growth in 2 '05 over 2004.
 In summary we expect the state's improving economy will provide a fairly dynamic operating environment in 2005. We want to thank you for your continued support of our company and we would now like to open it up for questions.

================================================================================
Questions and Answers
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [1]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (OPERATOR INSTRUCTIONS). Heather Wolf, Merrill Lynch.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Heather Wolf,  Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [2]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning, I was just curious the guidance that you gave in the third quarter with respect to your net interest margin was very similar to what you said today. That you expect hedging losses and a slight decline in your margin. But that is clearly not what you posted this quarter, so I am curious what the change was.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [3]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is David. I'm looking at the guidance that you provided in the fourth quarter -- that the street head -- and we were basically at what I'm looking at is that the net interest margin that we've posted at 4 33 9 is about $3 million off of the analyst average. So 3 million box is not that much of a difference, fourth quarter estimate, or guidance versus the consensus fully.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Heather Wolf,  Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [4]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You had said -- if I remember correctly you said you posted a margin of 398 in the third quarter and the third quarter conference call you had said to expect a decline sequentially in the margin. Am I wrong on that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [5]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I don't have that in front of me, but I do know the basis of our guidance. And the guidance that we have is based on about $434 million, and the average of the analyst is 439. So you know, the numbers are very different. I don't remember off the top of what we did have been there but those are the actual numbers.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [6]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You are giving her net interest income. She is asking about margins.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [7]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. Well, the margin that we had in our consensus -- actually, we don't forecast or provide guidance on margins. However, the estimate that we had was 403, and the consensus was 436, but we don't really provide the guidance for margin. We do provide it for net interest income.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Rice,  Union Bank of California - VP, IR   [8]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Heather, this is Jack Rice. Why don't you and I get together after this call and I will clarify that. I think we're talking at cross purposes here.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Heather Wolf,  Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [9]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Can you give the loan and deposit growth extraction from Federal. Was the only loan contribution $750 million in the commercial real estate portfolio?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [10]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, the average fourth quarter growth represented by Jackson was 750. Because they were not there for the full quarter. The whole portfolio is 900 million-ish.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Heather Wolf,  Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [11]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay and on the deposits did you give that number?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [12]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 With Jackson's deposits?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Heather Wolf,  Merrill Lynch - Analyst   [13]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [14]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, -- do you recall Jackson's deposits? Around 400 million? Yes, not a big number.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [15]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Harvey. Fox-Pitt Kelton.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Harvey,  Fox-Pitt Kelton - Analyst   [16]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you. Just trying to follow up on the previous caller's question. I'm just trying to understand the guidance here about the margin declining. Until the Fed fund gets 3 percent yet we saw this quarter an actual increase in the margin. I'm just trying to understand what happened this quarter that is not going to happen in the future? Or what benefit that you might have had this quarter that you're not going to have in the next few quarters?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [17]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 In the fourth quarter, we did have some interest back-end or backed out from loans that basically came in that were charged off and they came in -- there was a small amount of that. And that was one of the bigger components of that. The other one is -- hold on for one second -- I've got the analysis here. In fact, I will come back and answer that in just a few minutes once I get to our margin analysis.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [18]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Let me give you a little broader view of net interest margin. It is very hard to predict within a couple basis points in any -- for any particular quarter. Deposits were up more than we thought they would be in the fourth quarter. That affects it. We had some interest recoveries on previous nonaccrual loans. That affects it. Going forward, we think that the net interest margin is going to hang around for 100 basis points, give or take, until we get toward the end of '05, at which point, assuming our outlook on rates is correct, we're going to start to see it rise gradually.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Harvey,  Fox-Pitt Kelton - Analyst   [19]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just looking at the balance sheet. It appears to be very liquid, and the thought of loan growth still being very robust in '05, it just sounds like there seems to be a lot of opportunities to redeploy a lot of that excess liquidity into some good earning assets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [20]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You are right and as I tried to explain we're not a big taker of interest rate bets. Our base assumptions are that we will be running down the securities portfolio, generally speaking, to fund commercial and residential mortgage growth. So our total earning assets are not going to move that much over the course of the year. There is going to be a remixing into other asset classes.
 Some of these securities that are rolling off, we have been enjoying a pretty healthy margin on. To the extent we're replacing those with floating-rate loans, it's going to take a while for LIBOR -- which is what most of those are based on -- to make up that difference. Now you're right, we could if we wanted to lever up the balance sheet, given our liquidity, and take some longer bets on securities. We will have to see how the year plays out, but we don't make a lot of bets that way.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Harvey,  Fox-Pitt Kelton - Analyst   [21]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just the last question. If you're not going to see that much balance sheet growth and there's going to be a lot of remixing this year, will you continue to be active on the buyback? You seem to have a bit of a stepped-up activity level in the second half of the year and you seem to be throwing off a lot of capital as well. Can you just discuss that?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [22]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is David again. First of all, I think the important thing is we plan to stay within our target, 7 to 8 percent. So that does give us flexibility as you mentioned. And as we look at our buyback programs throughout the year, we basically will first look at using the capital to handle balance sheet growth, secondarily, support our dividends, third, look at our acquisition opportunities and then, lastly, we look at our buybacks.
 And as we look into '05 -- we make these decisions every quarter, and as we look into '05 we see there is opportunities for considering those areas. That area.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Harvey,  Fox-Pitt Kelton - Analyst   [23]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, it just seems like the stock buyback would be very accretive to earnings at these sort of levels.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [24]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 They would be.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [25]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Manuel Ramirez. Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Manuel Ramirez,  Keefe Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [26]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. Two quick questions for you. First, how should we think about the relationship between deposit fees and rising interest rates? I don't have a great sense for how much your deposit fees are consumer-based, how much is commercial. Presumably the commercial is more rate sensitive, meaning seasonal decline has rates rise. Then I have a follow-up question.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [27]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, our DDA is, very roughly, half and half. And the commercial part of course is all on analysis. And as rates rise, earnings credits are going to go up, and our customers will have the opportunity to pay for their banking services through the enhanced earnings on their deposits they have here rather than deposit fees. So in my comments on CSFG, I pointed out that we expect very modest deposit fees increases because of that. And that's what we experienced between '03 and '04.
 On the other hand, the deposits are quite valuable, of course.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Manuel Ramirez,  Keefe Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [28]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, I was just trying to think of if there was a rule of thumb, that you should be thinking about in trying to model things out. In other words, short rates go up 100 basis points, you increase your earnings credit rate by 50 basis points, as X percent impact on fees.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [29]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We are positively leveraged on deposits to gain as rates go up, even though people will not be paying those deposit fees, we more than make it up.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Manuel Ramirez,  Keefe Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [30]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 On the margin?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [31]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Manuel Ramirez,  Keefe Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [32]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And in the second question, and I know this is a loaded question but -- what would you consider a normalized long-term loss rate on your current loan portfolio? I don't think history is really a great guide, as you suggested. You have changed the mix a lot to create a more stable portfolio over time, which I certainly think a lot of a significant payout. But in your mind, what is a number we should be thinking about out in 2006, 2007?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [33]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, Manny, you're absolutely right. It's a very different portfolio. I'm sorry, I'm getting an echo. it is a different portfolio so history is not much of a guide. We had about 10 basis points of losses in '04 which I certainly would not guide you to as a long-term reasonable loss rate. You know most people would say a bank that is heavily involved in commercial lending would, you know, something around 50 basis points might be over all the cycles a reasonable level.
 I read your note this morning, and I think the point you were making on us having some risk on the guidance for provision, all hinges really on what we think is going to happen on losses in '05. Our best estimate right now, and we are pretty familiar with the portfolio, absent something really unusual happening, we think losses are going to be sort of like 04's. In other words, very very low.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Manuel Ramirez,  Keefe Bruyette &amp; Woods - Analyst   [34]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay so a little bit of a decline in the reserve-- losses should be low. Now how much of that hinges on recovery? Your gross losses, I think, were 30 basis points in 2004 but you also had significant recoveries. Do you see a lot of stuff coming through the pipeline? Is that a lot of the syndicated credits that you charged off a while ago?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [35]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 You know, you have heard me talk about the stuff in my previous role at the bank -- I'm amazed at the recoveries we had 'cause back in the early part of the cycle in say '01 we sold so many loans. But we've had tremendous recoveries. I would have bet they would have declined a while ago. And yet we had what? 24 million of recoveries against 20 million of gross charge-offs in the fourth quarter. So I'm not prepared to call the recovery gravy train over yet.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [36]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrea Jao. Lehman Brothers.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrea Jao,  Lehman Brothers - Analyst   [37]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. Returning to the guidance which is a range of 20 cents, could you give more detail in terms of assumptions that went into the lower end of guidance versus assumptions that went to the higher end of guidance? It seems that the $20 million weighing in the provisioning accounts for less than 9 cents. So what else goes into the 20 cent difference?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [38]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 This is David. And it is the variabilities of the interest rates that could impact us. And additional -- you know, in the volumes in our balance sheet. Those are big drivers as well as the provision.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Andrea Jao,  Lehman Brothers - Analyst   [39]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. Thank you. My second question is, what is the impact of Jackson Federal in the fourth quarter, and could you talk about the role of their higher cost CDs and replacing those with your lower-cost balances?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [40]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I will handle the second question. The guidance that we provided in '05 is integrated the runoff of the CDs in it. So the changed balance sheet is reflective in the guidance that we provided in the first quarter as well as the full year. And the second one, David, excuse me Phil, you probably have it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [41]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes. Jackson was probably worth a basis point or maybe 2 in the net interest margin. Not a whole lot. But it -- you know -- it helps if we are trying to parse it down to the basis point.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [42]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jed Gore (ph). Sanova (ph) Capital.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jed Gore,  Sanova Capital - Analyst   [43]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Good morning. Thanks for a great year and I guess we need to compliment you on exceeding your guidance for the past couple of years. I think that demonstrates your guidances in a conservative range by design. Just want to ask you is the buyback from your parent still an option that is on the table? Is that something you guys investigate?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [44]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is one of the choices or one of the options that we consider year in, year out as you probably recall. Last year, we did not exercise it, did not use that as one of our alternatives or considerations, because we have acquisitions that we found to be attractive to us in the prior two years, we did, because we found that there were not as many attractive alternatives then by a trade with our majority owner.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jed Gore,  Sanova Capital - Analyst   [45]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Just a question for follow-up -- thank you -- on Jackson. Have you discussed what the earnings accretion will be from that deal in 2005?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [46]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Say again? Can you say that one more time?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jed Gore,  Sanova Capital - Analyst   [47]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Have you discussed what the earnings accretion will be from Jackson for the year 2005?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [48]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No, we have not. It is of course, total, it is all baked into the '05 guidance.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jed Gore,  Sanova Capital - Analyst   [49]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So it is safe to assume that the deal is accretive?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [50]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [51]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Townsend. Friedman Billings Ramsey.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Townsend,  Friedman Billings Ramsey - Analyst   [52]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Most of my questions have been answered, but perhaps Rick could discuss Fresno in your new deposit or new branching approaches.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rick Hartnack,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [53]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, Gary. Let me just turn real quickly as I got a couple of stats in front of me here, just to make me more confident in answering the question. We now have, I think, pretty convincing evidence that what we call the power bank we talked about briefly before here, really is working from a standpoint of market share and accelerated deposit growth. What is still an issue for us is the cost of doing it. And it is an investment that we just have to be cautious about, because we have continued to keep a real jealous eye on EPS growth. So I think that you can look at 2005 as a year where we continue to perfect our approach in the test markets and prepare ourselves for further rollout.
 But I don't think that it would be appropriate to look at it having a major effect on the rest of our operations during 2005. You know, we just have to play this balance between investment for future earnings growth and producing the kind of earnings that our investors want in the short-term and I think we have got that balance about right and feel confident we do have a marketing approach that will benefit us in the long run.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Townsend,  Friedman Billings Ramsey - Analyst   [54]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 So the Midcoastal extension seems to be producing similar results to those that you saw in Fresno?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rick Hartnack,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [55]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes to give it a little more color I would say, you know, we tried the Central Coast because the branch density for us was not as great throughout that region as we had in Fresno. So it was a slightly different test for us. Santa Maria, for instance, we really only have one branch so we really don't have the -- you know we really don't have been quite the parity and convenience.
 Having said that, we are now getting good results in the Central Coast. It took a little longer to produce the kind of posited numbers we saw almost immediately in Fresno. But now, the numbers are solidly positive when compared to the rest of the bank. So we feel good about this for sure, but as I said, it is a pretty stunning investment, and it is in some respects it's not unlike opening a new branch. Great investment for the future but it really hurts in the short run.
 And the next markets we roll out are going to be just much bigger, so the cost impact is much greater. And you know, we have -- we have got to be careful about this.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Townsend,  Friedman Billings Ramsey - Analyst   [56]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Did the experiment cost a penny in 2004, would you say or have you looked at it from that standpoint?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rick Hartnack,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [57]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Hang on just a second. Yes, that is about right. Yes, that is about right.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Gary Townsend,  Friedman Billings Ramsey - Analyst   [58]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thanks. Once again, good year, good quarter. Keep it up. Thanks again.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [59]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney, Sanders Morris.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [60]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David, can you give us a reconciliation to net interest income contributions in the fourth quarter from Jackson Federal? And then also loan recoveries? I think you mentioned there was some. Can you give us a dollar amount for that, and then I have a follow-up.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [61]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, I'm going to actually have Jack reconcile that off-line.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [62]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay, that's fine.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [63]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 What did you want on the loan recoveries?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [64]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, do you have that number? I know it was modest but can you give me that number?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [65]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 For the fourth quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [66]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [67]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It was $24 million.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [68]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 24.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [69]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It was not modest. That's a huge number of recoveries in the quarter against gross charge-offs of 20.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [70]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (technical difficulty)-- I'm sorry interest income and net interest income level.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [71]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Net interest income.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [72]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Recovered interest income from charge-off loans.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [73]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That was like, what? About $4 million. Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [74]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And double check with Jack on that one. We don't have that schedule right here.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [75]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And then Phil, where are you getting traction in your C&amp;I portfolio, volume in energy business, media, can you give us an idea of industries where you are seeing some good pickup?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [76]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure I can give you some breakdown on that, if you want. In the fourth quarter the commercial loan, commercial banking area went from 3.5 billion of average loans to 3.65 billion, so pretty good pickup there. Our energy area grew by a couple of hundred million dollars. The corporate market grew by about $30 million, so it was pretty spread out.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [77]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 And are you doing participated occasions anymore or is that (technical difficulty) done?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [78]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well what we do now is we're certainly still in the syndicated loan market.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [79]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right but were you participating? (multiple speakers)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [80]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We act as an agent on a lot of stuff. We also act as a participant but when we act as a participant, it is in conjunction with other relationship business like deposit to our business, for example. We're not just out buying pieces of loans in the leverage market like we were doing back in '98, '99.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Campbell Chaney,  Sanders Morris - Analyst   [81]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Great. That answers that. And if I could have one tiny follow-up. On your capital management I think, David, you said you discussed every quarter whether doing buyback dividends and those kind of thanks. Have you done that for this quarter?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [82]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well we have a Board of Directors meeting coming up next week, and we will review it with our Board on that basis.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [83]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Kahn from Sandler O'Neill.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Kahn,  Sandler O'Neill - Analyst   [84]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I just wanted to follow-up -- most of my questions have been answered -- but on the Jackson Federal acquisition, I think the most recent data suggested that the balance sheet was roughly 1.3 billion on both loans and deposits. And it sounds like a lot of that that is runoff from the deposit side was the higher cost CDs. But on the asset side, did you guys also run off a piece of the loan portfolio?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [85]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. Not yet, the numbers -- this is Phil. I was talking about the commercial loan piece fees which (inaudible) real estate areas. There were some other odds and ends that went into Rick's area. I don't think it is probably changed so much (multiple speakers)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Rick Hartnack,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [86]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 We have not taken any actions to runoff (multiple speakers)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [87]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. (multiple speakers). And remember there is only two months of the, so in the average fourth quarter (multiple speakers) I'm talking about.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Brian Kahn,  Sandler O'Neill - Analyst   [88]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That probably explains --
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [89]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It has not dramatically changed on the asset side since we bought it.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [90]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard. Morgan Stanley.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [91]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I have a question, Phil. You're giving some guidance on commercial loan growth next year. And I was talking about the $600 million increase in escrow loans. (multiple speakers)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [92]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is loans to title companies.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [93]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Exactly. Loans to title companies. And are these -- you know what is your -- do you have any of these under balance sheet today? And is that 600 million sort of the average balance sheet you expect over in full-year numbers next year or is that what you expect it to get to buy the end of next year?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [94]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. What I was referring to was the increase in those loans. During '04 we averaged around call it 150 million-ish. And with rates rising, we expect a lot more usage of those lines by the title companies. So we will average around 750 million or so in '05.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [95]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Are we at sort of an interest rate level yet where that becomes an attractive option for title companies to start to choose these?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [96]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Oh yes, they have already started drawing down and really right at the start of the year.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [97]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And as these loans increase should we see a decline in vendor expenses?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [98]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 No. Probably vendor expenses go up as well because we're earning a lot on the deposits. And then counter to that is the lending activities as well as the vendor bills.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [99]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Are these loans usually made at prime minus?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [100]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 These are very cheap loans. They are detractive of the net interest margin. (multiple speakers) I should not say that, on only the asset side because we're making it up on the deposit side.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [101]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Right. So even with the deposits, do you think this is greater than your average margin?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [102]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Greater than our average margin. What do you mean?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [103]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, the spread between the loans and the deposits.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [104]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It is still -- it is an advantageous deposit for us to gather. It is certainly not the cheapest deposit we gather, but it is cheaper than going out in the market for example and in buying wholesale, and it is cheaper than large brokered CDs, for example.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [105]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (inaudible) You had mentioned I think, a 6 percent decline in title escrow deposits year-over-year on average?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [106]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That is our best guess.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Chris Chouinard,  Morgan Stanley - Analyst   [107]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That seems a little low. What is your -- is this just consistent with the rate assumption that you laid out at the beginning of the call?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [108]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well you know, this time last year I would have told you that title escrow deposits were going to decline and in fact they grew point to point 3 percent. This is our best estimate. I could be wrong. I think just given our market share and what a great job our people do in this business, if I'm wrong I'm guessing I'm wrong in being overly conservative in the drop. (multiple speakers)
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [109]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joe Morford. RBC Capital Markets.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joe Morford,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [110]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I wondered if you could just give us a status of the DSM agreement with the Fed, and the timing of when that may be reviewed next and possibly list it so you could more actively pursue acquisitions again?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [111]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Sure. We entered into the agreement between Union Bank of California International and in the Fed last quarter. And it had a whole series of steps that we needed to do and comply with. We are meeting all of our requirements. We are moving through all the steps that we agreed to take with the Fed. And as far as we know the Fed is satisfied with our actions. As far as when we will completely satisfy the Fed, I cannot give you an estimate on that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joe Morford,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [112]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Okay. And then just a separate follow-up question, you talked to guidance. Did not include options expense for the second half of the year. What would you expect that to be?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [113]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 It's about 4 cents a quarter.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Joe Morford,  RBC Capital Markets - Analyst   [114]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 4 cents a quarter. Great, thanks so much.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [115]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (OPERATOR INSTRUCTIONS). Kathy Steinbrecher with Piper Jaffray.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kathy Steinbrecher,  Piper Jaffray - Analyst   [116]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 My question is on non-interest income, the other category. If you exclude the private equity, what else is in that line item?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [117]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Fourth quarter versus linked basis?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kathy Steinbrecher,  Piper Jaffray - Analyst   [118]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yet.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [119]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Basically we had an increased amount of standby letters of credit of about $2.6 million. And we had a small sale of a real estate, roughly $4 million, $3 million.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kathy Steinbrecher,  Piper Jaffray - Analyst   [120]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 (inaudible) real estate? Oh okay. Could you also tell me what the value of the securities that were sold was?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [121]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well, we took -- how much was the total amount that we sold?
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Kathy Steinbrecher,  Piper Jaffray - Analyst   [122]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [123]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 That was about $1 billion. Re-invested in reducing our debt, our short-term funding. And basically increased our asset sensitivity a little bit.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [124]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lana Chan with Advest.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lana Chan,  Advest - Analyst   [125]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 I just had a follow-up question on the margin again. And what the assumptions were in terms of the interest rate hedges starting to roll off I guess when short-term rates hit 3 percent. But then I had thought that the margin would start benefiting after that from higher rates, but it seems like now you're saying that the margin is going to not really benefit through the rest of 2005. Right now, the Fed funds is pricing in the short-term rates are going to hit 3 percent by the middle of '05. So I just wanted to reconcile that.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 David Matson,  Union Bank of California - EVP and CFO   [126]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Yes, that is what we guess as well. We think that the margin will be improving in the third and fourth quarters. So we agree with what your estimates are. And in terms of -- I mean, I think one of the things that we all would want to make sure that our investors understand is the rate sensitivity that we have against our -- if rates increase faster than what we start with, that rates increase more than what we predict in our interest rate scenario. And while this is not directly connecting to your question is, I think it gets close to it. And that is if we have a parallel shift increase of 25 basis points, we expect to have accounting increase, accounting net interest income, of about $3 million, but an economic net interest income of about breakeven.
 So that ties to the parallel shift and then a flattening of the yield curve which would be the other side of this, is that if we have long rates going down, that we end up with basically an accounting and net interest income going down about 1.5 million and quarterly economic net interest income going down about $600,000.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Phil Flynn,  Union Bank of California - Vice Chairman   [127]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Lana, let me just go back to the net interest margin impact. In the fourth quarter, the hedges rolling off were worth about 13 basis points. And our best guess is for the first two quarters, each quarter, it will take down about 10 basis points. And after that, it is about half of that in the third quarter, maybe five, and then almost nothing in the fourth quarter. So they are running down pretty quickly through the year.
 As for the impact on the net interest margin goes.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [128]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 At this time, we're showing no further questions.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Jack Rice,  Union Bank of California - VP, IR   [129]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Well if that is the case, then, thank you all very much for joining us on the call and I'm available to handle follow-up. Have a nice day.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Operator   [130]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Thank you, and ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude our conference for today. The call will be available today for replay at 1-800-475-6701 for folks dialing from the United States or Canada. Or from outside the U.S. or Canada, please dial 320-365-3844 and at the prompt enter the access code of 762-604 (ph). That call will become available today, Friday, January 21st, the 12 noon Pacific time and will be available through next Friday, January 28, at midnight Pacific time. And that does conclude our conference for today. Thanks for your participation and for using AT&amp;T's executive teleconference. You may now disconnect.

]]></Body>
  </EventStory>
  <eventTitle><![CDATA[Q4 2004 UnionBanCal Earnings Conference Call]]></eventTitle>
  <city>SAN FRANCISCO</city>
  <companyName>MUFG Americas Holdings Corp</companyName>
  <companyTicker>UB.N^K08</companyTicker>
  <startDate>21-Jan-05 4:30pm GMT</startDate>
</Event>